- Are you ready, kids?
- 孩子们，你们准备好了吗？
all:
Aye, aye, Captain!
全部：
是啊是啊，队长！
- I can't hear you.
- 我听不到你说话。
all:
Aye, aye, Captain!
全部：
是啊是啊，队长！
- ♪ Ohh... ♪
- ♪ 哦...♪
♪ Who lives in a pineapple
under the sea? ♪
♪ 谁住在菠萝里
在海底？ ♪
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- ♪ Absorbent and yellow
and porous is he ♪
- ♪ 吸水性和黄色
他是多孔的 ♪
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- ♪ If nautical nonsense
be something you wish ♪
- ♪ 如果航海废话
成为你想要的东西♪
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- ♪ Then drop on the deck
and flop like a fish ♪
- ♪ 然后落在甲板上
然后像鱼一样扑通扑通♪
all: SpongeBob SquarePants!
- Ready?
所有：海绵宝宝！
- 准备好？
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
SpongeBob SquarePants!
- SpongeBob
- 海绵宝宝
SquarePants!
方裤！
[laughing]
[笑]
♪ ♪
[waves crashing]
[海浪拍打]
[ominous music]
[不祥的音乐]
♪ ♪
[bubbling]
[冒泡]
[laughter]
[笑声]
[inhaling]
[吸气]
♪ ♪
[cranking]
[启动]
[spitting]
[随地吐痰]
[gurgling]
[淙淙]
- [laughs]
- [笑]
- [humming]
- [嗡嗡声]
- Hey, Sandy.
- 嘿，桑迪。
- Hey, SpongeBob.
- Check out our new balloon.
- 嘿，海绵宝宝。
- 看看我们的新气球。
- Her name is Squeaky.
- 她的名字叫吱吱。
[squeaking]
[吱吱声]
- Sorry, guys, I'm working on
my new invention.
- 对不起，伙计们，我正在努力
我的新发明。
Y'all better
come back tomorrow.
你们都好点了
明天回来。
[exclaiming]
[惊呼]
both: New invention!
两者：新发明！
- See?
- 看？
[whirring]
[呼呼]
both: Ooh.
两人：哦。
- What is it?
- 这是什么？
- It's a portal
to other worlds.
- 这是一个门户
到其他世界。
I built it to explore
the universe.
我建造它是为了探索
宇宙。
Also for quick trips
to Texas to pick up
也适合快速旅行
前往德克萨斯州接载
some of my favorite
barbecued nuts.
一些我最喜欢的
烤坚果。
Yoink!
哟哟！
- Huh?
Dagnabbit!
- 啊？
该死！
That ding-dang,
nut-stealing arm is back again!
那个叮当，
偷坚果的手臂又回来了！
[munching]
[咀嚼]
- Pretty nifty, huh?
- 很漂亮，是吧？
- Yeah.
- 是的。
Nifty.
漂亮。
Ooh, what's this do?
哦哦，这是做什么的？
Vroom, vroom, vroom!
[screeches]
呜呜呜呜！
[尖叫声]
[exclaiming]
[惊呼]
- [beeping]
- [嘟嘟声]
[exclaiming]
[惊呼]
[laughter]
[笑声]
- Hold it,
don't touch anything.
- 握住它，
不要碰任何东西。
I gotta go grab some 1/16 inch
diodes to finish this weld.
我得去拿一些 1/16 英寸的
二极管来完成这个焊接。
♪ ♪
- Patrick, you heard Sandy.
- 帕特里克，你听到桑迪的话了。
We shouldn't touch this,
or this, or this,
我们不应该碰这个，
或者这个，或者这个，
or this, or this, or this.
或者这个，或者这个，或者这个。
[beeping]
[嘟嘟声]
[laughing]
[笑]
- Definitely don't do this,
SpongeBob.
- 绝对不要这样做
海绵宝宝。
[giggles]
[咯咯笑]
Or this.
[exclaiming]
或者这个。
[惊呼]
- And under no circumstances
should you ever touch this.
- 并且在任何情况下
你应该碰一下这个吗？
Boink.
操。
[alarm blaring]
[警报声]
[whirring]
[呼呼]
both: Whoa.
两人：哇哦。
[stammering]
[结巴]
- [gasps]
Oh, no!
- [喘气]
哦，不！
You've activated the vortex!
你已经激活了漩涡！
- Ooh, so swirly.
- 哦，太旋涡了。
- Look at all the colors.
- 看看所有的颜色。
[exclaiming]
[惊呼]
- Whatever you do,
don't walk into it!
- 无论你做什么，
不要走进它！
- Can we skip into it?
- 我们可以跳进去吗？
[exclaiming]
[惊呼]
- SpongeBob SquarePants,
Patrick Star,
- 海绵宝宝，
帕特里克·斯塔,
you stop right now!
你现在就停下来！
Now turn around.
现在转身。
Now walk.
现在步行。
♪ ♪
[gasps]
[喘气]
Oh!
[groans]
哦！
[呻吟]
Those two ain't no smarter
than a circus peanut.
这两个人并不聪明
比马戏团的花生。
[screaming]
[尖叫]
[exclaiming]
[惊呼]
[horse whinnies]
[马嘶声]
- Wow!
- Whoa!
- 哇！
- Oh, oh!
- 哦，哦！
[exclaiming]
[惊呼]
- Goodness.
- 天哪。
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
Mm, mm.
嗯，嗯。
- Wow.
- 哇。
We've entered
a whole new dimension.
我们已经进入了
一个全新的维度。
Uh, a blank, white, empty one.
呃，一张空白的、白色的、空的。
- Must be the boring dimension.
- 必须是无聊的尺寸。
Let's go home.
我们回家吧。
- Maybe there's
an exit this way.
-也许有
出口是这样的。
Huh, hmm, must've made
a wrong turn.
呵呵，一定是做出来了
转错了方向。
Huh?
啊？
[panting]
[气喘吁吁]
Patrick, there's no escape!
There's no escape, Patrick!
帕特里克，无路可逃！
无处可逃，帕特里克！
- [sobbing]
I can't take it!
- [抽泣]
我受不了！
Let me out of here!
让我离开这里！
[panting]
[气喘吁吁]
[exclaiming]
[惊呼]
♪ ♪
- [panting]
- [screeches]
- [气喘吁吁]
- [尖叫声]
- Hmm.
- Huh?
- 唔。
- 啊？
both: Ooh!
两人：哦！
[grunts]
[咕哝]
Mm...
毫米...
[laughs]
Oh, Patrick, watch this!
[笑]
哦，帕特里克，看这个！
[grunts]
Boink.
[咕哝]
操。
[humming]
[嗡嗡声]
- [laughs]
- [笑]
[motor revs]
[电机转速]
[grunts]
- Whoops, sorry!
[咕哝]
- 哎呀，抱歉！
- Heh, draw some more!
- 呵呵，再画一些吧！
♪ ♪
- Nice décor.
- 漂亮的装饰。
Hmm.
唔。
[humming]
[嗡嗡声]
[light music]
[轻音乐]
♪ ♪
- Oh, my house!
- 哦，我的房子！
Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, ah!
Hey!
啊啊啊啊啊啊啊啊！
嘿！
- Oops, forgot to draw
the ground.
- 哎呀，忘记画了
地面。
♪ ♪
[thud]
- [grunts]
[砰]
- [咕哝]
[groans]
[呻吟]
[rumbling]
[隆隆声]
Ahh.
啊。
I'm starving.
我饿死了。
- No problem.
- 没问题。
Two patties coming right up!
两块肉饼马上就上来了！
- [gasps]
- [喘气]
♪ ♪
- Your doodle patty, sir.
- 你的涂鸦馅饼，先生。
- [chomps]
- [咀嚼]
- [grunts]
- [咕哝]
Tastes weird.
味道怪怪的。
- Yeah, they are a little dry.
- 是的，它们有点干。
♪ ♪
- I miss real Krabby Patties.
- 我想念真正的蟹黄饼。
- I miss Mr. Krabs.
- 我想念蟹老板。
- I miss Sandy.
- 我想念桑迪。
- I miss Gary.
- 我想念加里。
both: I miss Squidward.
两人：我想念章鱼哥。
- You know who
I miss most of all?
- 你知道是谁
我最想念的是？
SpongeBob.
海绵宝宝。
- But Patrick, I'm right here.
- 但是帕特里克，我就在这里。
- [babbling]
- [胡言乱语]
- Aww, isn't he cute?
- 哇哦，他不是很可爱吗？
- How do you do?
- 你好吗？
- [babbles]
- [胡言乱语]
- Ooh, I'm next
on the hug list.
-哦，下一个是我
在拥抱名单上。
- Oh, oh!
He disappeared!
- 哦，哦！
他消失了！
Oh, why was I cursed
with the hug of death?
哦，为什么我被诅咒了
与死亡的拥抱？
Why?
- He's not gone, Patrick.
为什么？
- 他没有走，帕特里克。
He's right there
on your tum-tum.
他就在那里
在你的转轮上。
- [grunts]
- [咕哝]
all: [babbling]
全体：[胡言乱语]
[exclaiming]
[惊呼]
- [giggling]
- [咯咯笑]
[chomping]
Oh!
[咀嚼]
哦！
all: [exclaiming]
全体：[惊呼]
- Get 'em off!
Get 'em off me, SpongeBob!
- 把他们放开！
把他们从我身上拿开，海绵宝宝！
[chomping]
[咀嚼]
[exclaiming]
[惊呼]
- Hold on, Patrick!
- 坚持住，帕特里克！
[splashing]
[溅]
[screams]
[尖叫声]
- Oh, thanks, buddy.
-哦，谢谢，伙计。
- You're welcome.
- 不客气。
I guess we need to be
more careful.
我想我们需要
更加小心。
[bubbling]
[冒泡]
♪ ♪
[screaming]
[尖叫]
- [babbles]
- Nice DoodleBob.
- [胡言乱语]
- 漂亮的涂鸦鲍勃。
Put the pencil down.
把铅笔放下。
- [grunting]
- [咕哝]
[clang]
[铛]
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
- Oh, run!
- 哦，快跑！
[panting]
[气喘吁吁]
[exclaiming]
[惊呼]
[clanging]
[叮叮当当]
[panting]
[气喘吁吁]
What are we gonna do,
SpongeBob?
我们要做什么，
海绵宝宝？
- [grunts]
- [咕哝]
[whirring]
[呼呼]
We'll have to fight doodle
with doodle.
我们必须与涂鸦作斗争
与涂鸦。
[dramatic music]
[戏剧音乐]
Hold it right there.
把它握在那里。
You're no match
for my doodle squad!
你不是对手
为了我的涂鸦小队！
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
Attack!
攻击！
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
- [babbling]
- [胡言乱语]
♪ ♪
[babbling]
[胡说]
[grumbling]
[抱怨]
- Patrick, run!
- 帕特里克，快跑！
- Ooh!
- 哦！
- [babbling]
- [胡言乱语]
- [grunting]
- [咕哝]
[babbling]
[胡说]
- [babbling]
- [胡言乱语]
- Patrick, I'm going in.
- 帕特里克，我要进去了。
Cover me.
掩护我。
[grunts]
[咕哝]
- I gotcha, buddy!
- 我明白了，伙计！
- Huh?
Whoa!
- 啊？
哇！
[grunts]
[咕哝]
What?
Hey, where'd DoodleBob go?
什么？
嘿，嘟嘟鲍勃去哪儿了？
- Over here.
- Yipe!
- 在这里。
- 伊佩！
You let him go, Doodle.
你让他走吧，嘟嘟。
- [babbles]
- [胡言乱语]
- [exclaims]
- [惊呼]
- [babbles]
- [胡言乱语]
- [exclaims]
- [惊呼]
- [grunts]
- [咕哝]
- [yells]
- [大喊]
- [grunting]
- [咕哝]
[bell chimes]
[钟声]
- [grunting]
- [咕哝]
- [babbling]
- [胡言乱语]
♪ ♪
- [grunts]
- [咕哝]
Patrick!
帕特里克！
- [babbling]
- [胡言乱语]
[dramatic music]
[戏剧音乐]
♪ ♪
- Don't worry, Patrick!
- 别担心，帕特里克！
I'm coming for you!
我来找你了！
- Good to know!
- 很高兴知道！
- Surrender peacefully,
DoodleBob,
- 和平投降，
嘟嘟鲍勃，
or face the wrath of...
或面对...的愤怒
SpongeBob,
Knight of the Square Table.
海绵宝宝，
方桌骑士。
[grunts]
[咕哝]
Charge!
收费！
- [grunts]
- [咕哝]
- [grunting]
Ha-ha!
哈哈！
[thud]
[砰]
- [laughing]
- [笑]
- Release my friend
before I get really tough!
- 释放我的朋友
在我变得真正强硬之前！
- [babbles]
- [胡言乱语]
[screaming]
[尖叫]
- I gotcha, I gotcha!
- 我明白了，我明白了！
both: Oof!
两人：噢！
- [groans, gasps]
- [呻吟，喘气]
all: [babbling]
全体：[胡言乱语]
[thumping]
[怦]
[screaming]
[尖叫]
- What are we gonna do?
- 我们要做什么？
- [grunting]
- [咕哝]
- In here.
- 在这里。
[babbling]
[胡说]
Phew.
唷。
- Nah-nah, you missed us!
- 不不，你想念我们了！
Now you gotta kiss us!
现在你要吻我们！
- [babbles]
- [胡言乱语]
- Nah-nah...
- Patrick.
- 不不不...
- 帕特里克.
- What?
[gasps]
- 什么？
[喘气]
- [babbling]
- [胡言乱语]
- Oh, we'll never
get back home.
- 哦，我们永远不会
回家吧。
- We'll never see
our balloon Squeaky again.
- 我们永远不会看到
我们的气球又吱吱作响了。
- Oh, Squeaky.
[gasps]
-哦，吱吱。
[喘气]
Squeaky!
吱吱！
[panting]
[气喘吁吁]
Grab on, buddy!
抓住吧，伙计！
all: [babbling]
全体：[胡言乱语]
- [babbles]
- Too slow, DoodleBob!
- [胡言乱语]
- 太慢了，DoodleBob！
- [babbling]
- [胡言乱语]
- Uh, SpongeBob.
- 呃，海绵宝宝。
all: [babbling]
全体：[胡言乱语]
- [panting]
Here, Patrick.
- [气喘吁吁]
在这里，帕特里克。
- Oh, ooh, uh...
snip.
- 哦，哦，呃...
剪断。
[screaming]
[尖叫]
all: [babbling]
全体：[胡言乱语]
- Well, that's the end
of DoodleBob.
- 嗯，就这样结束了
涂鸦鲍勃。
- But we're still stuck here.
- 但我们仍然被困在这里。
- Oh, yeah.
- 哦，是的。
Too bad Sandy isn't here.
可惜桑迪不在。
She'd find a way
to get us back home.
她会找到办法
让我们回家。
Wait a minute, Patrick.
等一下，帕特里克。
♪ ♪
Doodle us home, Sandy.
桑迪，在我们家涂鸦。
- [babbles]
- [胡言乱语]
Bleeble blobble blortex!
Bleeble blobble blortex！
Bleeble blobble blotex！
[whirring]
[呼呼]
both: Yay!
两人：耶！
Thanks, Sandy!
谢谢，桑迪！
- Whoo!
- Whoo-hoo-hoo-hoo!
- 呼！
- 呼呼呼！
♪ ♪
- Hmm, mm-hmm...
- 嗯，嗯嗯……
[whirring]
[呼呼]
What the--?
什么——？
[whirring]
[呼呼]
- Sandy, we're back.
- 桑迪，我们回来了。
[crinkling]
[起皱]
[inhaling]
[吸气]
- I ain't fixed the vortex yet!
- 我还没修好漩涡！
How in tarnation
did you get back?
如何在塔内
你回来了吗？
- Sandy saved us.
- 桑迪救了我们。
- What?
- 什么？
Huh?
啊？
- Give me back my nuts!
- 把我的坚果还给我！
- [gulps]
- [吞咽]
♪ ♪
- [laughs, babbles]
- [笑声，胡言乱语]